there are two memory Technologies sram
and dram
sram stands for static Random Access
memory dram stands for Dynamic Random
Access memory The Random Access Part in
both names Simply refers to the fact
that We can Access Any memory location
by Address Without needing to go through
all the memory locations so Random
Access is as opposed to sequential
Access Like a Tape Where You have to
actually Scan through the whole Tape to
get some
with memory We can arbitrarily Access
Any Part of the memory Without really
needing to get to it so the only
difference between sram and dram is  this
static or Dynamic behavior static in
sram refers to the fact that sram
retains Its Data while the power is
supplied so As long as you Connect It To
A Power Source It's going to retain the
Data that you wrote to it It's Not going
to Lose It Dynamic in dram means that It
Will Lose Data Even while connected To A
Power Source unless We Refresh The Data
so Pretty much We need to read Out The
Data and write it Back In And keep doing
that on a regular basis otherwise dram
will Simply  Lose our Data not that both
of  these types of memory will Lose Data
When the power is not supplied Such as
When we Turn them off so it seems like
sram is better We like it use We don't
have to do anything in Order for It To
keep The Data whereas witham We actually
have to Access The Data and write it
back in in Order for It To not Lose It
so Why do We want to have dram the
answer is that for sram several
transistors are needed for each bit of
sram whereas for dram We only need One
transistor Per bit  so obviously We can
get a lot more diram Per Unit Area than
We can
SR so SR is good it retains Data but Bad
Because It's more Expensive Here We have
to Refresh The Data to keep it alive but
We can cram A lot of these Bits on a
Chip it turns Out There is Another
difference Which is sram is typically
faster and dram is typically slower so
We Get Speed ​​and simplicity at more Cost
or We can go slower and need to work at
it but have more Bits